bom.gov.au 2019-07-01

# Online privacy notice - Bureau of Meteorology

This privacy notice applies to user interaction with the Bureau of Meteorology’s website ([www.bom.gov.au](http://www.bom.gov.au/)). 

For further information about our agency’s privacy practices and your rights, see the full Bureau Privacy Policy - March 2014 or contact:

**FOI & Privacy Coordinator**  
Bureau of Meteorology  
People Management Branch  
GPO Box 1289  
MELBOURNE VIC 3001  
Tel: 03 9616 8428  
Email: [privacy@bom.gov.au](mailto:privacy@bom.gov.au)

* * *

### Overview

We may collect personal information when you use our website or email us where it is reasonably necessary for, or directly related to, the performance of our functions or activities. 

Personal information is defined as information about an identifiable individual, or someone who can be reasonably identified. 

* * *

### Personal information you provide us online via our website or email

When you use our online subscription and feedback forms, or email us we will record and use your personal information (including your email address) for the purpose for which you provided it. Only authorised staff will have access to your personal information. We will not disclose your personal information without your express or implied consent, unless an exception under the Privacy Act applies.

Please be aware that as the Internet is an unsecure medium, there is a risk that unencrypted information submitted via our online forms or email may be intercepted, read or modified. If you prefer not to contact us online, you can contact us by phone or mail. 

* * *

### Site visit data

When you visit our website a record of your visit is logged. The following information is collected from your browser and recorded for statistical purposes:

  * the type of browser you are using
  * the date and time of your visit
  * your top level domain name (for example .com, .gov, .au, .uk etc.)
  * the address of the referring site
  * your server’s IP address (a number which is unique to the machine through which you are connected to the Internet: usually one of your service provider’s machines)
  * the addresses of the pages you access and any documents downloaded.

We record this data to maintain our server and improve our services. We do not use this information to personally identify you unless an exception under the Privacy Act applies, including where we reasonably believe that the use or disclosure is reasonably necessary for enforcement related activities conducted by, or on behalf of, an enforcement body.

* * *

### Cookies and Web beacons

The Bureau uses cookies, web beacons and measurement software and tools on this websites and other government website and we allow our services providers and third parties such as our analytics, advertising or ad serving partners to do so. We use and disclose the information collected through the use of cookies, web beacons and measurement software and tools in accordance with this Privacy Act. This includes using the information to report statistics, analyse trends, administer our services, diagnose problems and target and improve the quality of our products and services. We may allow other third parties to use their own cookies and web beacons to collect information about your visit to this website and other government website.

We may combine information collected through the cookies and web beacons on this websites and other government website with information collected by third parties using their own cookie and web beacon, to provide better or more relevant services and advertising to you on this websites and other government website. Our service providers and other third parties may do the same in order to provide more relevant services and advertising to you through other websites that you may visit.

* * *

### Cookie Choice

If you do not wish to have information collected through the use of cookies, web beacons or measurement software and tools, you can delete or reject cookies through your browser setting or the settings section of your mobile or tablet device. Disabling cookies may cause some of the functions on this websites and other government website to not function correctly.

* * *

### Google analytics

In addition to web server logs, our website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (Google). Reports obtained from Google Analytics are used to help improve the efficiency and usability of our website.

Google Analytics uses cookies to help analyse how users use our website. The information generated by the cookie about this (including IP addresses) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers around the world.

Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating the use of our website, compiling reports on website activity for site operators and providing other services related to website activity and internet usage. Google may transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate user IP addresses with any other data held by Google. You can opt out of the collection of information via Google Analytics by downloading the [Google Analytics Opt-out browser add on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB).

However, by using our website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. For further information please refer to Google's Privacy Policy at: <http://www.google.com/privacy.html>

* * *

### Searches

Search terms that you enter into the search engine on our website are recorded, but there is no link made between search terms and your personal details. The search terms you use are not associated with any other information that we collect. We use this information for statistical means to ascertain what people are looking for on our website and to improve the services that we provide.

* * *

### Links to other sites

Our website contains links to other sites, for example to Facebook and YouTube. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these linked sites and have no knowledge of whether cookies or other tracking devices are used on these linked sites. Similarly, some products used on our website are provided by an external internet service provider. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of any external provider.

If you have any concerns regarding your privacy when visiting a linked site or using an external product, you should review the relevant external privacy policy.

* * *

### Revision of this statement

From time to time, we will review and revise this statement. We reserve the right to amend this statement at any time and any amendments will be notified by posting an updated version on our website at [www.bom.gov.au](http://www.bom.gov.au/)

_This statement was last updated on 12 March 2014._

* * *

### Privacy impact assessments register

Privacy impact Assessment reference number | Project name  | Brief description of project | Commencement date  
---|---|---|---  
20190321 | Travel and expense management tool | The implementation of SAP concur as a travel and expense management tool. | 4/4/19
